# **Azizul Hakim Tareq**

I've around 2 years of experience in software development and seeking a challenging position to use my talents and skills to grow and expand the organization and gain more experience.

+88 01836765672 azizultareq7@gmail.com Dhaka, Bangladesh

Portfolio: https://azizultareq.netlify.app Github Linkedin

## **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Engineer**

December 2021- July 2023

**Eucaps** 

Stockholm, Sweden (Remote)

- Worked at an international fintech company and build product which is currently used by 1 million users.
- Worked from start to finish of a SaaS product and worked both on frontend and backend of the application.
- Responsible for writing API, writing complex database query, building interactive user interface etc.
- Responsible for doing frontend code review and provide feedback to team mates.

# **Software Engineer**

September 2021 - November 2021

Najj Technologies Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developing and maintaining web applications, managing servers and database, designing and developing APIs, building frontend with React
- Currently developing both frontend and backend of an application where tutors can offer courses/classes and students can enroll in the course. The system will block course fees while enrolling in a course
- Other features live class, screen sharing, whiteboard, assign and submit assignments, different functionalities for different users, etc.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Javascript, Typescript, C++

**Backend:** Nodejs/Express

Frontend: React, Nextjs, Vuejs, Redux, React query, Pinia, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Material Ui, Bootstrap

Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Others: Docker, Git, Github, Nginx, Heroku, Netlify, Vercel, Jira, Postman, etc.

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- Solved 500+ coding problems from various online judges like codeforces, codechef, hackerrank, LightOJ, etc.
- Participated in 70+ codeforces, codechef, atcoder contests.
- Skilled in data structure, algorithm, common problem-solving techniques, OOP etc.

# **EDUCATION**

# **North South University**

January 2017- May 2021

- BSc in Computer Science & Engineering
- Relevant Coursework: Algorithms, Database, Data Structure, Concept of Programming Language, Operating

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Rent Abode Live → Code →

• Anyone can post his property like home, apartment, hotel, resort etc. on the platform and any user can have booking on those abodes by searching and selecting his preferred abode. Multiple users can't book an abode on same data.

• Stack: Nextjs, Typescript, Mongodb, Prisma, NextAuth, TailwindCSS etc.

Bestfit Shop <u>Live</u> Code

• Features – shopping cart, user rating and comment, quantity select, user profile page, payment system. Admin can add, edit, delete products, delete user, make a user as admin, check orders, and mark ordersas delivered.

• Stack: React, Nodejs/express, Redux, React Bootstrap, Mongodb, HTML, CSS etc.

# **Tour Packages** (Team Project)

Paper **↗** 

- Using the developed web application, users can view and sign up for booking a package and pay for that tour package using stripe. Each advertised tour contains information regarding the tour and users can view reviews written by previous travelers, users can view the location of the tourist spots. There is a user profile page that shows the booked tour packages, the user cannot book two tour packages on the same date. Admins can add, edit, and delete a tour package.
- Stack: Nodejs, MongoDB, PUG template, mapbox API

Place Review Preview 

Code 

Preview 

Code 

Preview 

Preview

- A user can select any place from the map and can give a review and rating about that place, user needs to register and sign in to be able to do this. Users' data and places data are stored in MongoDB..
- Stack: React, Nodejs, Mongodb, HTML, CSS, mapbox API etc.

Covid-19 Data Tracker Live Z Code Z

- Covid-19 Data Tracker is an app made using React, which tracks covid-19 data for more than 200 countries and regions. Data is provided by an API. Users can search data for any country or region.
- Stack: React, HTML, CSS

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

1. G. K. Anik, A. H. Tareq, M. A. Haque Abir, M. H. Islam and M. M. Khan, "Development of Web Based Tour Package System," 2021 IEEE World AI IoT Congress(AlIoT), 2021, pp. 0313-0317,

DOI: 10.1109/AlloT52608.2021.9454226 7

2. A. H. Tareq, M.A.Abir, G.K. Anik, M.Ariful K., Dr. Rashedur Rahman, Skin Disease Classification Using Machine Learning Techniques - IWANN 2021: International Work Conference on Artificial Neural Networks DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-85030-2 49 7